Rick Vermeil

Software Engineer

Erie, CO (610) 202-1418 rickv85@gmail.com Portfolio GitHub | LinkedIn

As a former Content Marketing Manager and Product Owner, I bring a unique blend of project management, web content expertise, and Agile development leadership to the table. My background has instilled a deep sense of user empathy, which compels me to create software that is not just functional, but also highly intuitive and user-friendly. I thrive in challenging environments that encourage continuous learning and innovation.

SKILLS

Languages / Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, Sass, Tailwind, HTML, SQL, Node.js Systems / Practices: Software Development, Object Oriented Programming, UI/UX Development and Design, Web Development, Unit Testing, End to End Testing, Test Driven Development, Git, GitHub, Redux, Figma, RESTful APIs, Agile Methodologies, Continuous Integration and Deployment

PROJECTS

Backcountry Bookings | Repo | 4/2023 | 7-person team

Tech: React, TypeScript, Rails, Ruby, Sass, CSS, HTML, Cypress, Google Maps API, AWS S3 Bucket, Git, GitHub

Led frontend development and coordinated as Product Manager on a full-stack team that built a U.S. National Park campground search and review platform, which was awarded first place in Turing's "Demo Comp" by a panel of experts in the software industry.

Ride Ready | FE Repo | BE Repo | 3/2023 - Present | Solo project

Tech: React, JavaScript, Sass, CSS, HTML, Cypress, OAuth2.0 API, Node.js, Express, SQL, Heroku, Git, GitHub

Integrated OAuth 2.0 authentication with Strava to leverage a user's ride data, enabling the precise calculation of remaining service life for mountain bike suspension in accordance with manufacturer guidelines.

<u>Lav Link</u> | Repo | 2/2023 | 4-person team

Tech: React, JavaScript, Redux, Sass, CSS, HTML, Cypress, REST API, Google Maps API, Git, GitHub

Engineered a React and Redux-based app to solve the real-world problem of locating user-specific restrooms, featuring filters for unisex, ADA-accessible, and changing table amenities to customize user experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Frontend Developer - Vermeil Web Solutions LLC, Erie, CO - May 2023 to Present

- Designed and built a highly responsive portfolio website with a focus on elegant mobile display for a professional photographer. The site utilizes a mix of client-side and server-side rendering with Next.js 13 to optimize performance and search engine rankings.
- Developed a WordPress-based website tailored for a client, integrating a theme, migrating their content, and applying custom CSS to meet specific design aesthetics.

Content Marketing Manager / Product Owner - Bestop Inc., Louisville, CO - July 2020 to August 2022

- Led a team of developers as the Product Owner of a multi-brand e-commerce website development project.
- Increased project efficiency while reducing spend by over 30%.
- Managed and created all e-commerce website content via WordPress and BigCommerce.

Marketing Specialist - Bestop Inc., Louisville, CO - November 2013 to July 2020

- Coordinated and managed budgets for 80+ consumer and trade events per year.
- Planned and successfully executed a high profile trade show exhibit for five consecutive years.
- Coordinated 40+ photo and video shoots per year, creating all marketing assets for product merchandising.

EDUCATION

Front-End Software Engineering - Turing School of Software and Design, Denver, CO Apr 2023

Bachelor's of Science, Business / Marketing - West Chester Univ. of PA, West Chester, PA

May 2010